<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gregorio Cabral]]></title><description><![CDATA[A personal site and blog]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 17:39:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[El Blog Inicial de Gatsby]]></title><description><![CDATA[Escrito por  Kyle Mathews , quien vive y trabaja en San
Francisco, construyendo cosas útiles.
 Deberías seguirlo en Twitter]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/es/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/es/</guid><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Escrito por &lt;strong&gt;Kyle Mathews&lt;/strong&gt;, quien vive y trabaja en San
Francisco, construyendo cosas útiles.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kylemathews&quot;&gt;Deberías seguirlo en Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gregorio Cabral]]></title><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/</guid><content:encoded></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Master Checklist]]></title><description><![CDATA[4 minute read TL;DR I set up a checklist system with daily tasks and goals aiming to make sure that I grow professionally and personally…]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/master-checklist/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/master-checklist/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4 minute read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up a checklist system with daily tasks and goals aiming to make sure that I grow professionally and personally while having a balanced life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The struggle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reading career development blogposts and self development books, listening podcasts interviewees talk about their morning rituals or discussing “productivity” habits with friends, I often test the techniques and hacks they describe and sometimes get to see how they could improve my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I keep wondering how could it be possible for me (and even for them) to incorporate all these activities into everyday life, coordinate them so that they could all coexist and keep them going there for the time they require to actually produce the real claimed benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for example, I would often question myself, how could I make sure everyday I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sleep enough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;workout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stretch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;drink enough water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;floss&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have medical checks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get enough deep work hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take online courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finish side projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about-this-blog&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/deliverate-practice&quot;&gt;read, learn and memorize stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/quantifying-life&quot;&gt;stay close to family and friends&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in the quest to find a system that would help me track all these so that I can trust the process and relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The proposed solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution I am currently trying out is, of course, a master checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first wrote down a list with everything productive that I was happily doing everyday and added everything else that I wanted to incorporate to my routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, came what I consider the most valuable part of the system: quantifying the dedication to each activity. I decided how much time I would spend doing each of the activities. I &lt;a href=&quot;/quantifying-life&quot;&gt;divided the day into 48 blocks&lt;/a&gt; of 25 minutes with 5 minute break in between. Then, I assigned  a certain amount of blocks (or fractions of them) to each activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are items from the list, like fasting hours, that are not activities but behaviors. For those I assigned zero blocks, but should be quantified somehow in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I grouped the activities by type, just to make sure I took care of all the &lt;a href=&quot;/success-and-fat&quot;&gt;global aspects I care about&lt;/a&gt; everyday. I also classified activities as &lt;a href=&quot;/cumulative-or-maintenance&quot;&gt;maintenance or cumulative&lt;/a&gt;, to easily get a sense of the impact of the activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I put them into a Google Sheet and converted it into a checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The results so far&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using this system every weekday for one month now. I am getting to do about 90% of the blocks and enjoy the repeated state of satisfaction at the end of the day that this is bringing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By going through the checklist a few times every workday and acting on it, I feel I am doing everything that is required to stay healthy, social and in continuous personal and professional growth, while still having around enough “free” hours a workday to do whatever else I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The master checklist is functional and reliable enough for it to be useful but there is of course a lot of room for improvement. I incorporated daily “meta-blocks”, allocated to review the daily progress that far and improve the system when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from regular tunings like adding/removing activities and adjusting durations, the main improvements I’m considering are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a scoring system for zero block items and activity prioritization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better accounting for activities in the times-per-week and times-per-month frequencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope in the future I can end up with a system that guarantees the growth and balance I mentioned before, keeps itself under continuous improvement and stays out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I might also end up finding this too demanding/unnecessary/insane. In that case I will abandon,  hopefully after expressing my reasons for doing so. In any case, I don’t feel I will regret testing it for another month and using some undeniable benefits while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, here I am, earning a tick on my daily blogging block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email me at greggocabral@gmail.com if you want access to the master checklist Google Sheet&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[About this blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[This blog is a place to store and expose my ideas and projects. You will find explanations of concepts I ponder and tutorials and guides on…]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/about-this-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/about-this-blog/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This blog is a place to store and expose my ideas and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find explanations of concepts I ponder and tutorials and guides on tools and systems I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write this blog to force myself to structure thoughts in an simple and consistent way, covering all the knowledge gaps that go unnoticed when I keep them in my head. This way I expect them to come out more fluent and easier to understand whenever I refer to them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could write all these and keep it in private, but I decided to expose it to the world to connect with likeminded people. Also, it’s a way to communicate concisely with people I already know, so that they can see what I do, how I do it and, hopefully, why I do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Acerca de mi]]></title><description><![CDATA[¡Este es mi primer post en mi nuevo blog falso! ¡Que emocionante! Estoy seguro que escribiré un montón de cosas interesantes en el futuro…]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/es/acerca-de-mi/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/es/acerca-de-mi/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;¡Este es mi primer post en mi nuevo blog falso! ¡Que emocionante!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estoy seguro que escribiré un montón de cosas interesantes en el futuro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, y aquí viene una gran cita de la Wikipedia sobre
&lt;a href=&quot;https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Huevo_de_pato_en_salaz%C3%B3n&quot;&gt;huevo de pato en salazón&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los huevos al salazón se hacen remojándolos en una solución de salmuera
durante unas tres semanas o más, manteniéndolos en un lugar oscuro y seco,
preferentemente en una despensa, alacena o armario. La velocidad con que los
huevos curan depende bastante del clima, en particular de la temperatura. Con
temperaturas demasiado frías, pueden no curar correctamente o tardar más
tiempo. En un clima tropical, como el filipino, bastan con tres semanas. Sin
embargo, en España por ejemplo, y dependiendo de la zona, podrían ser de 3 á 5
semanas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../hello-world/salty_egg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Huevo de pato en salazón&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[About me]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m a mechanical engineer currently based in Buenos Aires, working remotely as a software developer
for Paygarden. Some of my current…]]></description><link>https://greggocabral.github.io/about-me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://greggocabral.github.io/about-me/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m a mechanical engineer currently based in Buenos Aires, working remotely as a software developer
for Paygarden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my current interests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;software development in clojure, clojurescript and elm, data intensive apps, progressive web apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self funded businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;future of work and career design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self development, checklists, time management, languages and learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carpentry, container homes, campervans and functional interior design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>